Guide to the Anthony Edward Siegman Papers SC1171
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Publications
  - Traveling-Wave Techniques for Microwave Resonance Measurements, 1959 (Box 16, Folder 25)
  - Entropy and Cross-Relaxation in Spin Systems, 1960 (Box 16, Folder 26)
  - The DC Pumped Quadrupole Amplifier - A Wave Analysis, 1960 (Box 16, Folder 27)
  - Progress in Solid-State Masers, 1960 (Box 16, Folder 28)
  - Thermal Noise in Microwave Systems. I Fundamentals...2&3, 1961 (Box 16, Folder 29)
  - Zero-Point Energy as the Source of Amplifier Noise, 1961 (Box 16, Folder 30)
  - Microwave Phototubes and Light Demodulators, 1961 (Box 16, Folder 31)
  - Passive Phase-Distortionless Paramtric Limiting With..., 1961 (Box 16, Folder 32)
  - Quantum Fluctuations and Noise in Parametric Processes, 1961 (Box 16, Folder 33)
  - Photomixing Experiments with a Ruby Optical Maser and a...B.J. McMurtry and A.E. Siegman, 1962 (Box 16, Folder 34)
  - Microwave Modulation and De-Modulation of Light, 1962 (Box 16, Folder 35)
  - A Proposed FM Phototube for De-Modulating Microwave-Frequency, 1962 (Box 16, Folder 36)
  - Photoconductive Mixing Experiments Using Ruby Laser and...H. Inaba and A.E. Siegman, 1962 (Box 16, Folder 37)
  - Modulation and Direct Demodulation of Coherent and...Harris, McMurtry, & Siegman, 1966 (Box 16, Folder 38)
  - Nonlinear Optical Effects: An Optical Power Limiter, 1962 (Box 16, Folder 39)
  - Cyclotron Wave Amplification Using Simultaneous RF Coupling...S. Mao and A.E. Siegman, 1963 (Box 16, Folder 40)
  - Broardband Detectors for Microwave Modulation Light... McMurtry, Gaenzle, & Siegman, 1962 (Box 16, Folder 41)
  - "Optical Heterodyning and optical Demodulation at micro.frequs. Siegman, Harris, McMurtry, 1963 (Box 16, Folder 42)
  - Microwave Demodulation of Light Siegman, Harris & McMurtry, 1962 (Box 16, Folder 43)
  - Lossless Beam Combination for Optical Heterodyning A.E. Siegman & B.J. McMurtry, 1964 (Box 16, Folder 44)
  - Design Considerations for Laser Pulse Amplifiers, 1964 (Box 16, Folder 45)
  - Small-Mirror Transverse-Mode Control and Near-Field, 1964 (Box 16, Folder 46)
  - Frequency Translation of an He-Ne Laser's Output Frequency...Siegman, Quate, Bjorkhold&Francois, 1964 (Box 16, Folder 47)
  - A Technique for Optical Frequency Translation Utilizing...S.E. Harris and A.E. Siegman, 1964 (Box 16, Folder 48)
  - The Laser: An Astounding Beam of Light - A.E. Siegman, 1964 (Box 16, Folder 49)
  - Design Study for an Infrared Image Tube - H. Hayami and A.E. Siegman, 1964 (Box 16, Folder 50)
  - A Twisted-Mode Technique for Obtaining Axially Uniform...A.E. Siegman and V. Evtuhov, 1965 (Box 16, Folder 51)
  - Unstable Optical Resonators for Laser Applicatrions, 1965 (Box 16, Folder 52)
  - Effect of Gaussian Beam Spread on Phase Velocity Matching in CW...G.E. Francois and A.E. Siegman, 1965 (Box 16, Folder 53)
  - Pump Power Dependence of Ruby Laser Starting and Stopping Time - A.E. Siegman and J.W. Allen, 1965 (Box 16, Folder 54)
  - Obtaining the Equations of Motion for Parametrically Coupled...A.E. Siegman, 1966 (Box 16, Folder 55)
  - The Antenna Properties of Optical Heterodyne Receivers, 1966 (Box 16, Folder 56)
  - Progress in Quantum Electronics - A.E. Siegman, 1966 (Box 16, Folder 57)
  - Microwave Demodulation of Light Siegman, Harris & McMurtry, 1964 (Box 16, Folder 58)
  - Accurate CW Measurements of Optical Second-Harmonic Generation - Bjorkholm and Siegman, 1967 (Box 16, Folder 59)
  - Modes in Unstable optical Resonators and Lens Waveguides - Siegman and Arrathoon, 1967 (Box 16, Folder 60)
  - Preliminary Measurements of Laser Short-Term Frequency Fluctuations - Siegman, Daino, and Manes, 1967 (Box 16, Folder 61)
  - Absolute Frequency Stabilization of a Laser Oscillator... A.E. Siegman, 1967 (Box 16, Folder 62)
  - Intracavity Electro-Optic Frequency Tuning, Polarization - Carlson and A.E. Siegman, 1968 (Box 16, Folder 63)
  - Observation of Quantum Phase Noise in a Laser Oschillator - A.E. Siegman and R. Arrathoon, 1968 (Box 16, Folder 64)
  - Current Pushing of the Oscillation Frequency of a 6328 A He-Ne Laser - Arathoon and Siegman, 1968 (Box 16, Folder 65)
  - Further Measurements of Quantum Phase Noise in a He-Ne Laser - Arrathoon and Siegman, 1969 (Box 16, Folder 66)
  - Simple Analytic Expressions for AM and FM Mode-Locked Pulses - Siegman and Kuizenga, 1969 (Box 16, Folder 67)
  - Reflection and Refraction of Gaussian Light Beams at...Massey and Siegman, 1969 (Box 16, Folder 68)
  - Positive Column Population Calculations for the Evaluation of Dispersive Effects in He-Ne Lasers, 1969 (Box 16, Folder 69)
  - Comments on Pumping on a Swing - A.E. Siegman, 1969 (Box 16, Folder 70)
  - A Proposed Method for Measuring Picosecond Pulse Widths and... Siegman and Kuizenga, 1970 (Box 16, Folder 71)
  - Observation of an Enhanced Lamb Dip with a Pure Xe Gain Cell... Wang, Byer, and Siegman, 1970 (Box 16, Folder 72)
  - Fresnel Drag Technique for Determining the Spin-Axis - Massey and Siegman, 1970 (Box 16, Folder 73)
  - Absorption Coefficient, Transition Probability and Collision...Wang and Siegman, 1970 (Box 16, Folder 74)
  - FM-Laser Operation of the ND: YAG Laser - Siegman and Kuizenga, 1970 (Box 16, Folder 75)
  - FM and AM Mode-Locking of the Homogeneous Laser. I. Kuizenga and A.E. Siegman, 1970 (Box 16, Folder 76)
  - FM and AM Mode-Locking of the Homogeneous Laser. II. Kuizenga and A.E. Siegman, 1970 (Box 16, Folder 77)
  - Unstable Optical Resonator Loss Calculations using the Prony... Siegman and Miller, 1970 (Box 16, Folder 78)
  - Modulation Frequency Detuning Effects in the FM-Mode-Locked...Kuizenga and A.E. Siegman, 1970 May 4 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - A Course in Lasers and Optical Electronics For Engineering...A.E. Sigman, 1971 May (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Stabilizing Output with Unstable Resonators, 1971 May (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Observation of Quantum Phase Fluctuationsin Infared Gas...Manes and Siegman, 1971 July (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Laser Book List Sigman, 1971 Dec. (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Dispersive Explanation of the Spectral Behavior of Runge's Siegman, 1972 June (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Designing Unstable Resonators for Large-Bore Lasers A.E. Siegman, 1971 May (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Harmonic Mode Locking of the Nd: Yag Laser...Becker, Kuizenga and Siegman, 1972 Aug. (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Rotational Relaxation and Triplet State Effects in the CW Dye Laser...Seigman, Phillion and Kuizenga, 1974 April (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - An Anti-Resonant Ring Interferometer for Coupled Laser Cavities Siegman, 1973 Feb. (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Hollow-Cathode Transverse-Dis-Charge He-Ne and He-CD+ Lasers...Wang and Siegman, 1972-1973 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Hermite-Gaussian Function of Complex Argument as Optical Beam...Siegman, 1973-1974 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Simultaneos Q-Sqitching and Mode Locking in the CW ND: YAG...Kuizenga, Phillion, Lund, Siegman, 1973 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Active Mode-Coupling Phenomena in Pulsed and Continuous Lasers...Siegman and Kuizenga, 1973 Oct. (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Unstable Optical Reonators...Siegman, 1974 Feb. (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Diffraction Calculations Using Fast Fourier Transform Methods...Sziklas and A.E. Siegman, 1974 March (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Why the Sinc Function Should be Defined as (sinx)/x and Siegman, 1974 (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Analystic Expressions for Ultra-Short Pulse Generation...Becker, Phillion, Kuizenga, Siegman, 1974 March (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Rotational Diffusion and Triplet State Processes in Dye Laser...Phillion, Kuizenga and Siegman, 1974 April 29 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Mode Calculations in Unstable Resonators with Flowing...Siegman and Sziklas, 1975 Aug. (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - How to Compute Ywo Complex Even Fourier Transforms...A.E. Siegman, 1974 (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - Subnanosecond Relaxation Time Measurements Using A...Siegman, Kuizenga, Phillion, 1975 April-June (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - Rotational Diffusion, 1974 April 29 (Box 18, Folder 24)
  - DC-Excited and Sealed-Off Operation of the optically...Max Artusy, N. Holms, and Siegman, 1975 Nov. (Box 18, Folder 25)
  - A Canonical Formulation for Analyzing Multi-Element...A.E. Siegman, 1975-1976 (Box 18, Folder 26)
  - Mode Calculations in Unstable Resonators with Flowing...I: Hermite-Gaussian. Siegman, Sziklas, 1974 Dec. (Box 18, Folder 27)
  - Interaction of Radiation with Matter A.E. Siegman, 1976 (Box 18, Folder 28)
  - Proposed Measurement of Subpicosecond Excited-State Measurement...A.E. Siegman, 1976 (Box 18, Folder 29)
  - Perturbed Gaussian Modes of Unbalanced Antiresonant-Ring...Shinan-Chur Sheng & A.E. Siegman, 1976 June 4 (Box 18, Folder 30)
  - Bragg Diffraction of A Guassian Beam by A Crossed-Gaussian...A.E. Siegman, 1976 (Box 18, Folder 31)
  - Effects of Small-Scale Phase Perturbations on Laser Oscillator...A.E. Siegman, 1977 May (Box 18, Folder 32)
  - Quasi fast Hankel Transform, A.E. Siegman, 1977 March 29 (Box 18, Folder 33)
  - Saturable Absorber Overlap of Iodine 127 With the...Max Artusy and A.E. Siegman, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 34)
  - Laser Cavity Dumping Using an Antiresonant Ring, Rickk Trutna and A.E. Siegman, 1977 Dec. (Box 18, Folder 35)
  - Neil's HG Laser Manuscript, 1977-1978 (Box 18, Folder 36)
  - Historical Note on Spatial Hole Burning and Twisted-...A.E. Siegman, 1978 March (Box 18, Folder 37)
  - The Optically Pumped Mercury Laser. N. Holmes and A.E. Siegman, 1971, 1976, 1978 (Box 18, Folder 38)
  - Dynamics of Energy Transport in Molecular Crystal: The...Salcedo, Siegman, Dlott, Fayer, 1978 July 10 (Box 18, Folder 39)
  - Pulse Vompression Inside an Actively AM Mode-Locked...Duerinckx, Vanherzeele, VanErc, 1969, 1978 (Box 18, Folder 40)
  - Laser Induced Photoacoustic Grating Effects in Molecular...Salcedo and A.E. Siegman, 1979 April (Box 18, Folder 41)
  - Pulse Stretching in a Q-Switch Nd: Yag Laser Schmid, 1979 Oct (Box 18, Folder 42)
  - Simplified Derivation of the Fokkker-Planck Equation A.E. Siegman, 1978 July (Box 18, Folder 43)
  - Diffraction-Based Unstable Ring Resonators with Possible Applications Shinan-Chur Sheng, 1979 Nov (Box 18, Folder 44)
  - Dynamic Holography/Interferometry Paper, 1979 Sept (Box 18, Folder 45)
  - Orthogonality Properties of Optical Resonator Eigenmodes A.E. Siegman, 1979 Oct (Box 18, Folder 46)
  - Resonant Modes of Optical Cavities with Phase-Conjugate Mirrors Belanger, Hardy, and A.E. Siegman, 1980 (Box 18, Folder 47)
  - Phase-Conjugate Reflection at Arbitrary Angles Using TEM00 Pump Beams" Rick Trebino and A.E. Siegman, 1979 Oct (Box 18, Folder 48)
  - Resonant Modes of Optical Cavities with Phase-Conjugate.. Belanger, Hardy, Siegman, 1979 Oct (Box 18, Folder 49)
  - Nonlinear Optical Calculations Using Fast Transform Methods: Second Harmonic..., 1979 Sept (Box 18, Folder 50)
  - Analysis of the Mode-Locked and Intracavity Frequency-Doubled, 1979 (Box 18, Folder 51)
  - Exact Cavity Equations with Large Output Coupling, 1989 (Box 18, Folder 52)
  - Cavity Equations for Laser Cavities with Large Output Coupling (Long Version), 1979 Aug (Box 18, Folder 53)
  - Picosecond Resonance Raman Spectroscope, 1980 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Retinal Chromophore of Rhodopsin...Hayward, Carlsen, Siegman, Stryer, 1981 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Passive Using An Antiresonant Ring Siegman, 1981 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Orthogonality Properties, 1982 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Elliptical Photoacoustic Cell...Heritier, Fouquet, Siegman, 1982 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Colliding Pulse Mode-Locing of a Nd:YAG Laser, 1981 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Mode-Locked Laser Oscillation, 1981 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Dense Electron-Hole Plasmas - Fauchet/Siegman (APL), 1983 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - "Additional Formulas for Stimulated Atomic Transitions" -AES, 1985 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Picosecond Spectr. using PA Detection, 1983 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Malachite Green Trebino/Siegman, 1983 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Optical Phase Conjugate Chapter Academic Press, 1983 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Top. Meeting on PA and Photothermal Spectr. (France), 1983 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - NATO Paper Italy, 1983 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Ul'fast.Spectr...Elec-Hole Plasmas. ICPS Fauchet/Siegman, undated (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - M.R. Symp., 1983 (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - N-Prism Beam...Talk S.W. Conf. on Optics Trebino. Barker, AES, 1985 (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - SPIE Picosecond Lasers and Applications, 1982 (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - A Comparison of Cassegrain....Rebino, Roller, Siegman, 1977 (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - New Picosecond Sources..AES/Vanherzezze, 1982 (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - Top Meeting on Psee Electron and Opto electron, 1985 March (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - Scottish Universities Summer School, 1982 (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - "Observation of the subpicosecond photovoltaic response in thin silicon-on-sapphire films", 1990 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - "Enhanced Schawlow-Townes linewidth in lasers with nonorthogonal transverse eigenmodes", 1990 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - "Frequency-domain observation of the ultrafast inertial response of the optical Kerr effect in CS2", 1990 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - "New developments in laser resonators", 1990 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - "Choice of clip levels for beam width measurements using knife-edge techniques", 1991 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - "Laser resonators: retrospective and prospective", 1990 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - "Defining effective radius of curvature", 1991 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - "Performance limitations of the self-filtering unstable resonator", 1992 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - "Technical writing and word processing using TeX", 1991 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - "Single-pulse laser beam quality measurements using a CCD camera system", 1992 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - "Stable-unstable resonator design for a wide-tuning-range free-electron laser", 1992 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - "Laser beam quality versus aperture size in a cw agron-ion laser", 1992 (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - "Computer display tools for lasers and optics", 1991 (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Crete BQ Review, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - "Respecting real-world problems of industry", 1992 (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - VRM Resonator Design, undated (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - "Output beam propagation and bq from a multimode stable-cavity laser" AES/Townsend (IEEE JQE), 1992 (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - "High power laser beams: defining, measuring and optimizing transverse beam quality" (GCL Conf. Crete, September 1992 (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - "Analysis of laser beam quality degradation caused by quartic phase abberations" AES (Appl. Opt.), 1993 (Box 14, Folder 30)
  - Madrid Manuscript, 1993 (Box 14, Folder 31)
  - "Binary phase plates cannot improve laser beam quality" (AES (Opt. Lett.), 1993 (Box 14, Folder 32)
  - "Effects of spherical aberration on laser beam quality" AES (SPIE, Boston, MA), November 1992 (Box 14, Folder 33)
  - "Defining, measuring and optimizing laser beam quality" AES (SPIE/LAX), January 1993 (Box 14, Folder 34)
  - "Singly resonant continuous wave mode locked parametric oscillator..." Chung/AES (JOSA B), November 1993 (Box 14, Folder 35)
  - Measurement of laser Quantum Freq. Fluctuations...Cheng, Mussche, AES, 1993 (Box 14, Folder 36)
  - SPIE Short Course 1-4, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 37)
  - SPIE Short Course 5-8, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 38)
  - SPIE video short course - viewgraphs, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 39)
  - G. Fanning, M. Fogliani, T. Kewitsch, J.R. Ruff and AES, "Subthreshold beam quality...on a wide-stripe diode laser" to Applied Physics Letters, 1993 (Box 14, Folder 40)
  - "Defining and measuring laser beam quality" AES (Elba Summer School, Plenum Press), 1992 (Box 14, Folder 41)
  - "Measurement of beam quality degradation due to spherical aberration in a simple lens" Ruff/AES (Opt. and Quant. Electron), 1993 (Box 14, Folder 42)
  - G. Nemes and A.E. Siegman, "Measuring All Ten Second Moments..." submitted to JOSA, 1994 (Box 14, Folder 43)
  - 10 Moments MS, 1993-1994 (Box 14, Folder 44)
  - A. E. Siegman, "Defining and Measuring Laser Beam Parameters" - Madrid, Spain, June 14-16, 1993 (Box 14, Folder 45)
  - Joon Chung and A. E. Siegman, "Optical-Kerr-Enhanced Mode Locking of a Lamp-Pumped, 1995 (Box 14, Folder 46)
  - S.A. Biellak, A.E. Siegman, "High Power Diffraction-Limited Reactive-Ion-Etched Unstable Resonator Diode Lasers" - submitted to CLEO, 1994 (Box 14, Folder 47)
  - Yuh-Jen Cheng, Paul L. Mussche and A.E. Siegman, "Cavity Decay Rate and Relaxation Oscillation Frequency" - to IEEE-JQE, 1995 (Box 14, Folder 48)
  - Beam Steerable SC Lasers...Sun, Francis, Biellak, AES, et al., 1994 (Box 14, Folder 49)
  - Lasers without Photons Appl-Physics B, 1994 (Box 14, Folder 50)
  - Laser Beam Quality - What's it good for? Proc. Lasers, 1995 (Box 14, Folder 51)
  - Lateral Mode Behavior of Reactive-Ion Etched...Biellak, Sun, Wong & AES, 1995 (Box 14, Folder 52)
  - Laser Beams & Resonators - Kobe, Japan, not dated (Box 14, Folder 53)
  - Wood's Anomaly Paper - Siegman/Fauchet JQE Special issue, 1986 (Box 14, Folder 54)
  - Optical Mode Properties of Laterally Offset Gain, etc. Yan Sun and AES (JQE), May 1996 (Box 14, Folder 55)
  - Quebec Mtg, July 1996 (Box 14, Folder 56)
  - ENF Meas. Ms. (PRL), 1996 (Box 14, Folder 57)
  - Rochester CQ07 MS, 1996 (Box 14, Folder 58)
  - Excess Quantum Noise... Cheng, Mussche, Fanning AES Opt. & Photon News, December 1996 (Box 14, Folder 59)
  - Transverse Mode Astigmatism...Cheng, Fanning, AES (AO), February 1997 (Box 14, Folder 60)
  - Reactive -Ion-Etched Diff-Limited...Biellak, Fanning, Sun, Wong, AES, 1997 (Box 14, Folder 61)
  - Axially Diode Pumped Unstable Reson. Nd: YVO4 Laser. Fanning, Cheng, AES, LEOS, 1995 (Box 14, Folder 62)
- Personal
  - Tony's Lab Books, Log Books, Diaries, & Calendars, 1962-2005 (Box 30)
- Biographical files
  - Legacy of Laser Education: Anthony Siegman article in Optics & Photonics News, 2014 Jul/Aug (Box 36)
- Laser equipment (Box 34, Box 35)
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-2017-173
  - External Hard Drive - "Tony's Raw HD", 2012 Jun 8 (Box 1)